A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
- The Alden Seminars - A White Paper: Massachusetts Higher Education in the Eighties: Proposals for Development (Reports 011748-008), 1983 (Box 526)
- The Alden Seminars - A White Paper: Massachusetts Higher Education in the Eighties: State Aid and Public Sector Tuition (Reports 011748-009), 1983 (Box 526)
- The Alden Seminars - A White Paper: Massachusetts Higher Education in the Eighties: Higher Education and the Schools (Reports 011748-010), 1984 (Box 526)
- The Alden Seminars - A White Paper: Massachusetts Higher Education in the Eighties: Improving the Public Schools (Reports 011748-011), 1984 (Box 526)
- The Alden Seminars - A White Paper: Massachusetts Higher Education in the Eighties: The New Technologies (Reports 011748-012), 1985 (Box 526)
- The Alden Seminars - A White Paper: Massachusetts Higher Education in the Eighties: New and Traditional Ethnicities (Reports 011748-013), 1985 (Box 526)
- The Alden Seminars - A White Paper: Massachusetts Higher Education in the Eighties: A Corporate-Academic Dialogue (Reports 011748-014), 1985 (Box 526)
- The Alden Seminars - A White Paper: Massachusetts Higher Education in the Eighties: Higher Education and Emerging Workplace Needs (Reports 011748-015), 1986 (Box 527)
- The Alden Seminars - A White Paper: Massachusetts Higher Education in the Eighties: Lifelong Learning and Recurrent Education (Reports 011748-016), 1986 (Box 527)
- Change in South Africa: processes, opportunities and constraints, Nov. (Reports 011749), 1978; Schlemmer, Lawrence (Box 527)
  07600373
  Blacks -- South Africa
- Black attitudes: adaptation and reaction (Reports 011750), 1975; Schlemmer, Lawrence (Box 527)
  Paper prepared for the Sixth Annual Congress of the Association for Sociology in South Africa (30th June - 3rd July 1975).
  Blacks -- Attitudes -- South Africa
- Preliminary report on recent developments in the Philippines (Reports 011751), 1986; Humphreys, John, 1943-; Kessinger, Tom G. (Box 527)
  Memorandum to Franklin A. Thomas. Discusses the Philippine Revolution of 1986, problems facing the Aquino government, and implications for Ford Foundation programming. Includes: list of Foundation grants and awards in the Philippines, Oct. 1985 - March 19
  Ford Foundation Philippines; Philippines -- History -- Philippines--History--Revolution, 1986
- The Ford Foundation Mar. (Reports 011752), 1972; Mayer, Robert A. (Robert Anthony) (Box 527)
  After brief introduction, report reviews the Foundation's support for libraries and library-related activities. Includes a memorandum from Mayer to Frank Sutton.
  1, 16 leaves.
  Libraries -- Endowments
- Program statements: Southeast Asia Regional Office, 1983 Mar. (Reports 011753) (Box 527)
  Briefing book prepared for visit by Franklin A. Thomas and William D. Carmichael to Southeast Asia. Contains 11 chapters of statements prepared by staff on the Ford Foundation's program strategies in the region.
  186 leaves in various foliations.
  Fair start for children (Indonesia);Women and employment (Indonesia);Resources and the environment (Indonesia);Water resources development program (Indonesia);Philippine program in water management;Uplands development (Philippines);Culture;Human rights -
  Child health services -- Indonesia; Natural resources -- Management -- Indonesia; Social forestry programs -- Indonesia; Social forestry programs -- Philippines; Women -- Employment -- Indonesia; Water resources development -- Indonesia; Irrigation -- Social aspects
- Microenterprise development as an employment and income generation strategy for the poor: experiences from the field, Oct. (Reports 011754), 1984; Stearns, Katherine E. (Box 527)
  Discussion is based on case studies of self-employment and small enterprise development programs in Africa, Asia, and Latin America. Includes bibliographical references. Prepared as a follow-up to the Employment and Income Generation meeting held by the O
  1, 65, 4 leaves.
  Small business -- Developing countries; Informal sector (Economics) -- Developing countries; Self-employed -- Developing countries; Poor -- Developing countries; Credit -- Developing countries
- Reflections on the Thai body politic and Ford Foundation programming (Reports 011755), 1989; Klausner, William (Box 527)
  Political planning -- Thailand; Political science -- Thailand
- An analysis of staff development programs and their costs in three urban school districts, Jan. (Reports 011756), 1980; Moore, Donald R. (Donald Roberts), 1942-; Hyde, Arthur A.; Designs for Change (Corporation) (Box 527)
  209 p.
  Teachers -- Job satisfaction; Teachers -- In-service training; Teachers -- Training of; Teacher-student relationships; Teacher-principal relationships; Teacher-school board relationships; Designs for Change (Corporation)
- Foundations and cultural development of the third world, Nov. (Reports 011757), 1981; Sutton, Francis X. (Francis Xavier); Rockefeller Foundation; Conference on International Philanthropy and the Humanities (1981: Bellagio, Italy) (Box 527)
  Prepared for the Rockefeller Foundation, Humanities Division, Conference on International Philanthropy and the Humanities in Bellagio, Italy, Nov. 16-20, 1981.
  Endowment of research -- Developing countries; Rockefeller Foundation; Conference on International Philanthropy and the Humanities (1981: Bellagio, Italy)
- Reflections (Reports 011758), 1985; Klausner, William (Box 527)
  Discusses social and political conditions in Thailand, and development organizations active there.
  Non-governmental organizations -- Thailand
- Returns to graduate education abroad: a Colombian case study, 1971 Feb. (Reports 011759), Harbison, Ralph W. (Ralph Warner), 1942- (Box 527)
  Research prospectus.
  70 leaves.
  Educational evaluation -- Colombia; Educational exchanges -- Colombia; Economic development -- Effect of education on; Colombian students -- Education (Graduate)
- The dynamic interaction of exchange rates and trade flows (Reports 011760-001), 1985; Branson, William H.; National Bureau of Economic Research (Box 527)
  08550392
  Free University of Brussels
  23, [6], 3 p.;28 cm.
  Conference on International Trade and Exchange Rates in the Late Eighties, June 6-8, 1985, Namur, Belgium.
  Foreign exchange -- Mathematical models; Equilibrium (Economics); Commerce -- Mathematical models; Portfolio management -- Mathematical models; National Bureau of Economic Research; Université libre de Bruxelles
- Trade and sectoral adjustment policy problems, International trade and industrial policy (Reports 011760-002), 1985; Klein, Lawrence R. (Lawrence Robert), 1920-2013 (Box 527)
  Industrial policy; International trade; Université libre de Bruxelles
- Modeling world trade (Reports 011760-003), 1985; Waelbroeck, Jean (Box 527)
  International trade -- Mathematical models; Commerce -- Mathematical models; Université libre de Bruxelles
- Comparative advantage in manufactured goods in a multi-country, multi-industry, and multi-factor model (Reports 011760-004), 1984; Balassa, Bela A.; Bauwens, Luc, 1952- (Box 527)
  Manufactures; Commerce -- Mathematical models; Comparative advantage (International trade); Université libre de Bruxelles
- Major recent developments in international trade theory (Reports 011760-005), 1985; Deardorff, Alan V. (Box 527)
  International trade -- Study and teaching; Université libre de Bruxelles
- Exchange rate misalignments and international trade (Reports 011760-006), 1985; Grauwe, Paul de (Box 528)
  International trade; Foreign exchange rates; Université libre de Bruxelles
- Exchange rates, policies and foreign trade: The case of Spain (Reports 011760-007), 1985; Fontela, Emilio; Duenas Pulido, Antonio (Box 528)
  International trade -- Spain; Exchange rate administration -- Spain; Université libre de Bruxelles
- Export price setting for selected sectors of the Belgian economy (Reports 011760-008), 1985; Cheffert, Jean-Marie; Deschamps, Robert; Reding, Paul, 1939- (Box 528)
  International trade
- South-south trade in manufactures - Implications for the north (Reports 011760-009), 1985; Ahmad, Jaleel (Box 528)
- International Monetary Problems and Trade: Speech by Mr. Willy De Clercq before the Conference on International Trade and Exchange Rates in the late Eighties, Namur, 6th (Reports 011760-010), 1985; Clercq, Willy de, 1927-2011 (Box 528)
- Exchange rates and trade: is there a problem for policy? (Reports 011760-011), 1985; Crockett, Andrew (Box 528)
- The high dollar and competitiveness: Policy issues for Europe (Reports 011760-012), 1985; Steinherr, Alfred (Box 528)
- Exchange rate strategies and real adjustment after the oil price shocks: the experience of the smaller European economies (Reports 011760-013), 1985; Söderström, Hans Tson, 1945- (Box 528)
- Meeting the needs and potential of informal firms through microenterprise promotion, 1985 (Reports 011761), Stearns, Katherine E. (Box 528)
  Based in part upon research done by Stearns as an intern and consultant for the Rural Poverty and Resources program of the Ford Foundation. Includes bibliographical references (p. 105-111). This is an expanded and substantially different version of Report
- Interaction of health technology and social organization: the Takemi lecture, Harvard School of Public Health (Reports 011762), 1984; Chen, Lincoln C.; Harvard School of Public Health (Box 528)
  Discusses impact of health care intervention on child mortality, based upon research conducted by the International Centre for Diarrheal Disease Research, Bangladesh (ICDDR,B) in Matlab Thana. Includes statistical tables.
  22, 12 leaves.
  Children -- Mortality; Child health services -- Developing countries; Child health services -- Research -- Bangladesh -- Matlab Thana; International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangladesh ICDDR,B
- The role of a private philanthropy in India (Reports 011763), 1984; Chen, Lincoln C.; Society For International Development (Box 528)
  Lecture presented to the Delhi chapter of the Society for International Development on Sept. 14, 1984. Discusses the history of and rationale for Ford Foundation involvement in India.
  Technical assistance -- India
- Middle East program: discussion paper (Reports 011764), 1973; Nelson, Courtney; Fredericks, J. Wayne (Jacob Wayne), 1917-2004 (Box 528)
  Discusses conditions in the Middle East, the objectives of the Ford Foundation's program there, and program strategies.
  Social sciences -- Arab countries; Technical assistance -- Middle East
- Ford Foundation history project (Reports 011765), 1985; Sutton, Francis X. (Francis Xavier) (Box 528, Reel R-9302)
  This report contains Sections II and III of the projected study. Reports #011012 contains draft of Section I and chapters on the Ford Foundation in Turkey and Nepal.
  Overseas development: part II
- Trip report, 1987 Sept.-Oct. (Reports 011766), McLean, Sheila Avrin; Micou, Ann McKinstry; Institute of International Education (New York, N.Y.). South Africa Programs. Information Exchange. (Box 528)
  Report on a trip to South Africa to collect data for the Information Exchange, "A U.S.-South African cooperative program to expand educational opportunities for black South Africans." -letterhead. The Information Exchange is under the auspices of the Inst
  08601048
  95 leaves.
  Education -- Research -- South Africa; Politics and education -- South Africa; Blacks -- Education -- South Africa; Institute of International Education (New York, N.Y.). South Africa Programs. Information Exchange.
- Public impressions of the Ford Foundation in the United States (Reports 011767), 1987; Wadsworth, Homer C., 1913-1994 (Box 528)
  Memorandum to the President and Board of Trustees, dated September 10, 1987.
- Significant features of the South African context (Reports 011768), 1987; Bonbright, David W. (Box 528)
  Apartheid -- South Africa; Human rights -- South Africa; Political science -- South Africa
- Visit to South Africa (Reports 011769), 1978; McLean, Sheila Avrin (Box 528)
  File memo dated January 10, 1978.
  42 leaves + attachment -- 28 cm.
  Apartheid -- South Africa; Political science -- South Africa; Human rights -- South Africa; Technical assistance -- South Africa; Endowments -- South Africa -- Evaluation; Southern Africa Project (Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law); South African Institute Of Race Relations
- A study of detention and torture in South Africa: preliminary report, 1985 Sept. (Reports 011770), Foster, Don; Sandler, Diane; University of Cape Town. Institute of Criminology (Box 528)
  08351051
  iv, 61 leaves.
  Detention of persons -- South Africa; Torture -- South Africa; University of Cape Town. Institute of Criminology
- Politics and crisis: reflections on the state of the Western Cape 1981-1987 (Reports 011771), Nasson, Bill (Box 529)
  36 leaves -- 28 cm.
- Physical and mental effects of unemployment on individuals and their families: report to the Ford Foundation 1977? (Reports 011772), Cottle, Thomas J. (Box 529)
  07490810
  Unemployment -- Psychological aspects; Unemployment -- Social aspects
- Information papers on South Africa and Namibia and Human Rights and Governance Programs (Reports 011773), 1990 (Box 529)
  Two information papers prepared for the June 1990 meeting of the Board of Trustees, June 27, 1990.
  Developing Countries Program/Eastern & Southern Africa;United States and International Affairs Program/Human Rights and Governance;Board of Trustees
  var. pag.: ill., tables, charts -- 28 cm.
  Human Rights and Governance program: site visits, Board of Trustees meeting, the Ford Foundation, June 28, 1990;Overview of program: South Africa and Namibia, Board of Trustees meeting, the Ford Foundation, June 27, 1990
  Human rights; Social justice; Political planning
- Project reports, 1971-1973. (Reports 011774), Darmadji, Suitinah, 1917-; Beeby, C. E. (Clarence Edward), 1902-1998; Pearse, Richard, 1932-; National Assessment of Education Project (Indonesia) PPNP
  Contains preliminary reports produced by PPNP on education in Indonesia: preschool education (by S. Darmadji), primary education (by C.E. Beeby), alternative courses of action in secondary education (by C.E. Beeby), and higher education (by Richard Pearse
  06900269;07200222.
  1 archives box containing 6 volumes (5 linear inches).
  Preschool education in Indonesia: progress report 1969-1971;Primary education;Secondary education, part c: alternative courses of action;Secondary education. part c, section 14-14:58: strategies for introducing change;Higher education in Indonesia;Perm
  Educational surveys -- Indonesia; Education -- Research -- Indonesia; Educational evaluation -- Indonesia; Educational planning -- Indonesia; Education, Preschool -- Indonesia; Education, Primary -- Indonesia; Education, Secondary -- Indonesia; Education, Higher; National Assessment of Education Project (Indonesia) PPNP
- Preschool Education in Indonesia: Progress Report, 1969 (Reports 011774-001), 1971; Darmadji, S. (Box 529)
  06900269;07200222
  Education -- Indonesia; National Assessment of Education Project Indonesia
- Trial Report Level III: Chapter on Primary Education (Reports 011774-002), 1971 (Box 529)
- Chapter VI: Level III Report: Secondary Education, Part C, Alternative Courses of Action (Reports 011774-003), 1972 (Box 529)
- Chapter VI: Secondary Education, Part C, Section 14-14-58: Strategies for Introducing Changes (Reports 011774-004), 1972 (Box 529)
- Level II Report: Higher Education in Indonesia (Reports 011774-005), 1973 (Box 529)
- Permanency of Literacy (Reports 011774-006), 1971 (Box 529)